engineersireland.ie 2018-12-26

# Engineers Ireland - Privacy Statement

#### Privacy Statement

##  1\. Introduction

We have created this Privacy Statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of your information and to explain to you our use of your information. The www.engineersireland.ie website (the “Website”) is operated by the Institution of Engineers of Ireland trading as Engineers Ireland (“we”, “us”, “our”, “Engineers Ireland”). In order to fully understand your rights, we encourage you to read this Privacy Statement and to consult our Terms and Conditions (the “Terms”).

This Privacy Statement (together with the Terms and any other documents referred to) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. If you are under 16 years of age, please read this Privacy Statement with a parent or guardian to make sure you understand it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Acts 1988-2003, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679 and any national implementing legislation (the “applicable Data protection law”), Engineers Ireland is the Data Controller.

##  2\. Information we may collect from you

We collect and process the following information:

  * Information that you provide to us when using this Website. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use this Website, subscribing to our services or purchasing goods, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by us, or our partners and when you report a problem with the Website.
  * Information you provide to us when applying through the Website for membership of Engineers Ireland, which will typically include your name and contact details and details of your relevant educational qualifications and work experience.
  * In group email initiatives including but not limited to, the weekly Training and Events Update, Engineers Journal email; Connect Corporate Newsletter, relating to email open rates, click-throughs, deliverability and site visits. This information is kept for the sole use of quality assurance and improving our email content and deliverability. You can unsubscribe from any email initiative using the links in the email footer of each individual email.
  * If you contact us for any reason, we may keep a record of that correspondence for as long as it is necessary regarding the nature of your contact.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them. We will always give you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such correspondence.
  * Details of transactions through the Website to which you are a party and of the fulfilment of your orders.
  * Details of your visits to the Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data and other communication data and the resources, advertisements and linked sites that you access.
  * Other personal information such as telephone recordings, CCTV images at our offices, web casts and images from conferences and other Engineers Ireland events.
  * Sometimes we may use your information when you are not a member. For example, a supporter for a membership application, a potential member or customer applying for one of our services, a volunteer or an employee or a job applicant.

##  3\. Where we store your personal data

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. In all such cases Engineers Ireland will only transfer such data where there is an adequate level of data protection in that country that is no less protective than that which is provided in Ireland.

##  4\. How we use your information

We use information held about you:

  * To ensure that content from our Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes or where it is in the legitimate interests of Engineers Ireland to provide you with this information;
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Website;
  * To notify you about changes to our Website and/or services.

We may also use your data to provide you with information about our goods and services which may be of interest to you (e.g. CPD Courses, publications) and we or our agents may contact you about these by post, email and telephone. You are free to unsubscribe and opt-out of this communication at any time and we will always provide you with a way of doing so. If you are happy for us to use your data in this way please tick the relevant boxes when we collect your contact preferences.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you (such as email, voicemail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous transaction with you.

We do not, without your consent, disclose information about identifiable individuals to third parties, but we may send anonymised statistical data to them for research and survey purposes. We may also use such information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, those in the engineering profession). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers’ wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience. We use Google analytics – information on this can be obtained at [www.google.com/analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics).

Engineers Ireland does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties.

Engineers Ireland may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Engineers Ireland may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Engineers Ireland, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Engineers Ireland does not gather special category data, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, from you.

The Engineers Ireland Website will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

(a) conform with a legal obligation;  
(b) protect and defend the rights or property of Engineers Ireland; or  
(c) to protect the personal safety of users of Engineers Ireland, or the public.

##  5\. Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your personal information to our subsidiaries or data processers working directly on our behalf for a specified purpose, for example, an external event management company obtaining delegate registrations for our annual conference. They do not keep this information and it is only used for the purpose we contract them for. We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Engineers Ireland, our members, or others.

##  6\. Safeguarding your personal information

We endeavour to use appropriate security measures at all times to protect your data. The Website has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. These security measures include SSL certificates to ensure encrypted data is received as it was sent, cookies and secure servers not accessible from anywhere but the Engineers Ireland Virtual Private Network (VPN). However, as no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed as 100% secure, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you transfer the data at your own risk

##  7\. Cookies

We may collect information about your computer, including where available, your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about how you browse our Website and is not specific enough to identify any individual user.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general Internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive. Cookies help us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:

  * To estimate usage numbers and patterns;
  * To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our Website according to your individual interests;
  * To speed up your searches;
  * To recognise you when you return to our site.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the Website or unable to avail of any of our services. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

Please note that our advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control.

##  8\. Your rights

We hope you are satisfied with the way in which we use your information. However, you have the right to tell us if you:

  * Don't want to be contacted in the future by us;
  * Would like a copy of the personal information which we hold about you;
  * Would like us to correct, update, or delete your personal information in our records;
  * Wish to report any misuse of your personal information.

If you would like to exercise any of these rights please do so by emailing us at [privacy@engineersireland.ie](mailto:privacy@engineersireland.ie) or writing to us at Engineers Ireland, 22 Clyde Road, Ballsbridge, Dublin D04 R3N2.

We hope you are happy with how we use your information but if you are not, you may lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Commissioner at [info@dataprotection.ie](mailto:info@dataprotection.ie)

##  9\. Acceptance of this Privacy Statement

By your use of this Website, you signify that you have read this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree with or you are not comfortable with any aspect of the Privacy Statement, we recommend that you discontinue use of the Website and your engagement with us.

We reserve the right to modify this **Privacy Statement** at any time. Your continued use of any portion of the Website following notification or posting of such changes will constitute your acknowledgment of those changes.

(May 18 2018)

Engineers Ireland, 22 Clyde Road, Ballsbridge, Dublin D04R3N2, Ireland | Tel: +353 (0)1 665 1300
